[A Moment But Forever]
[Episode 22]
You've come at just the right time.
The Immortal Dance
is about to begin.
There are still some good seats available.
Let me take you to have a look.
Thank you.
You two aren't from Yandu, are you?
Don't blink later.
This Immortal Dance
is unique to Yandu.
Countless scholars and refined guests
come here just to witness its beauty.
How is it unique?
Miss,
why do I feel like you look familiar?
You must have mistaken me for someone else.
You just said this dance is unique.
What exactly makes it unique?
This dance isn't performed by humans.
Not performed by humans?
Then by what?
The Immortal Dance is,
of course, danced by immortals.
Please enjoy.
You think Xiu would like this place?
Let me look around.
Xiu.
Xiu?
Bravo! Bravo!
Bravo!
Goddess?
She's the Goddess.
Everyone, look, the Goddess.
It really is the Goddess.
Look at her.
Goddess.
Goddess?
Don't go, Goddess.
How could you let her leave?
Slow down!
That dancer
in the painting did look like me.
Maybe someone saw me before
and painted me.
But I really don't know
what's going on.
Yuanzhong!
What are you looking at?
♫Listening♫
♫Toona leaves knock fireflies into a vase♫
♫Ripples faintly spreading♫
♫In the pavilion in the clouds♫
♫Warm wine brews to the sound of the zither♫
♫The fragrance lingers like brush strokes, sketching out your form♫
When I was young, I saw someone
who looked very much like you.
♫Tonight♫
♫In a light intoxication, I feel the longing in the crystalline snow♫
Was it at the Pinghu battlefield?
♫I cannot bear to think of you♫
As you know, I...
No.
♫I only wish♫
It was even earlier than that.
♫That the years would remain ever sunny♫
♫So that, within the drifting light, I could share the breeze with you♫
It's just that it has been so long
that I've forgotten
♫The wind blows♫
what she looked like.
♫It stirs the scenery♫
♫It awakens our heart♫
Who was it?
♫It makes me certain that you are my destiny♫
♫The closer we get♫
♫The more it feels like a dream♫
♫And the more I look intoxicated♫
♫I cannot fully express my yearning for you♫
I actually don't know either.
♫The wind blows♫
♫It blows away the shadows of the clouds♫
♫It makes the moon seem even brighter♫
♫It makes me wake up from a dream♫
♫The wind blows♫
♫It reddens my eyes♫
♫It warms the promise we made♫
♫In the wind, we gently♫
♫Drift into a better place♫
♫The wind blows♫
♫It blows away the shadows of the clouds♫
♫It makes the moon seem even brighter♫
♫It makes me wake up from a dream♫
♫The wind blows♫
♫It reddens my eyes♫
♫It warms the promise we made♫
♫In the wind, we gently♫
♫Drift into a better place♫
It's so quiet here.
Would Xiu be here?
He should be here.
The Divine Hand has already sensed it.
I'll try to wake him up.
Is there anything I can do?
No.
Xiu.
Xiu?
Xiu!
Dad,
why are we worshiping a firecracker?
Don't talk nonsense. This is the Fire God.
Disrespecting the gods
will get you slapped.
But this is clearly
just a big firecracker.
You don't understand.
This is our family's guardian deity.
It's the Fire God's manifested form.
This was passed down from your
grandfather's grandfather.
As long as it's here,
our family's fireworks shop
will be safe and sound,
with no disasters or misfortune.
Really?
Stop talking so much.
Just worship it.
If it weren't for the god's protection,
who could have made such a big firecracker?
Xiu,
go back to your position.
Who is it? Who is speaking?
Dad, Dad,
the Fire God seems to be about to explode!
What?
Dad, what should we do?
The Fire God is going to explode! It's going to explode!
You're right.
Xiu indeed likes lively scenes.
-Xiu, stop crying.
-Xiu.
Shut your mouth
right now.
Why does he keep crying?
Are you hungry?
Come on, think of a solution.
What can I do?
Isn't he your weapon spirit?
Don't you know the reason?
Well...
He wasn't like this the last time I saw him.
What was he like then?
He… he wasn't a baby.
At most, he was a child
and he was growing rapidly.
Do you remember
what he ate
to grow up?
At that time on Fangwai Mountain,
Zi Fei and Kai Shan were taking care of him,
so I didn't pay much attention.
Just think of a solution now.
He can't keep crying like this.
How about feeding him some wine
and getting him drunk?
He...
He's still a child.
He's a weapon spirit, not a child.
Xiu,
I know you can understand what I'm saying.
Shut up
right now,
or I'll stuff you back
into the firecracker.
There, there, there.
There, there.
Xiu, stop crying.
Stop crying. Stop crying.
Stop crying. Stop crying, Xiu.
There, there.
Stop crying, okay?
Stop crying. Stop crying.
There, there.
Stop crying, okay?
Yuanzhong.
Yuanzhong!
You try it.
There, there.
Stop crying,
Xiu.
Stop crying. Stop crying.
It's 1 AM, and the world is peaceful and safe!
Yuanzhong.
Yuanzhong, wake up!
Look at Xiu!
I can't handle him.
He's grown up.
Where is he?
X-Xiu.
Look.
The hairpin?
I remember now.
What do you remember?
Xiu doesn't eat ordinary food.
He needs to eat gold to grow up.
Eat gold?
Yes.
Xiu is of the fire element.
He feeds on gold.
Back then, on Fangwai Mountain,
Zi Fei and the others must have fed him
a lot of gold
to make him grow up in one day.
Feeding on gold?
But...
But we don't have any gold.
Xiu, Xiu.
I know you can understand me.
Let me tell you,
things are different now.
If you want to stay by my side,
you'll have to earn your own food.
Don't count on me.
Did you hear that?
-Yuanzhong.
-How dare you.
Yuanzhong!
He's still a kid.
He can't earn his own food yet.
Don't be so harsh on him.
He's young?
The number of people he killed on the Pinghu battlefield
was no less than mine.
That was on a battlefield. It was different.
He's just a child now.
Right, Xiu?
See?
If you rely on your master,
you'll probably starve
before you even grew up.
Alright, never mind.
I'll figure out a way
to earn food for him.
[Qiju Pavilion]
Mr. Xu,
if there's anything else that needs repairing,
bring it out for me.
There's nothing
I can't fix.
Alright, alright.
Yi, go and get everything
that needs repairing here.
Yes.
Don't touch it.
Mr. Xu, they're all fixed now.
Yi, go get the silver.
Wait a moment.
Miss Ji,
business requires honesty.
We agreed that
if you fix these things,
I'd give you 10 taels of silver.
You can't go back on your word.
What I mean is,
could you
exchange this silver
for gold beans?
Thank you.
Here.
Eat slowly.
They are all gone already?
Looks like raising a child
really is expensive.
How about
we go find Zi Fei?
The journey is long,
and the travel expenses
would cost money too.
But with how much Xiu eats,
even if we work ourselves to the bone,
we still won't earn enough gold.
Hey,
why didn't you bring any money
when you came out?
You didn't bring any either.
But I'm your handmaiden.
Bravo!
If we really can't figure out a way,
let's just let Xiu go hungry.
He's a weapon spirit. He won't starve to death.
How can we do that?
That way, he won't be able to grow up.
Then what do you suggest?
How about...
How about you
seal him away for now
and unseal him when Zi Fei and the others arrive?
Impressive.
You actually came up with that idea.
I'm starting to doubt
your identity as the Mute Lady of Wu Mountain.
Then what do you suggest we do?
Xiu?
Xiu!
Xiu is gone.
Where did this child come from?
What's going on?
My bracelet was stolen!
Let me take a look.
Excuse me,
have you seen a boy,
about 4 or 5 years old,
wearing red clothes?
Waiter, bring us the wine!
Coming!
Sorry, there are a lot of people here.
I honestly didn't notice.
Please look for him yourself.
Do you think he might be here?
Let's split up and look for him.
What are you dawdling for?
You're about to go on stage.
Be quick.
I'll be ready soon.
I just need to wear a hairpin.
Hurry up.
Where did it go?
It was here just now.
Which hairpin?
The one from Mr. Dong,
the gold one.
It should be in the jewelry box.
My earrings and necklaces
are also missing.
What's going on?
Whose child is this?
All mine are gone.
Whose child is stealing?
Exactly.
Such a young kid,
and his parents don't even supervise him.
Xiu, come out.
You...
-He ran away!
-Xiu!
He stole things!
Xiu.
Where did this child come from?
Xiu?
-Stop running.
-Xiu!
Let's see if you dare run again.
I told you not to run around.
Xiu, give it to me now.
Stop them!
Stop him!
It's him!
Pay up! Pay up!
You thief!
Pay up!
Xiu is asleep?
He's sleeping like a pig.
We were lucky today that Mr. Xu
was willing to lend us money.
Otherwise,
it wouldn't have been so easy to get away.
He's sleeping so soundly.
He's full,
so of course he's sleeping soundly.
When you said you thought he was a hassle earlier,
I thought you were joking.
Now,
I've really experienced it.
Raising a child really isn't easy.
He's not a child.
But he looks like one.
Look at him now.
He looks about 3 or 4 years old.
But...
why can't he speak yet?
What did he look like when he grew up?
Just like that.
Was he well-behaved?
He was fine.
I've never seen
a weapon spirit
that can grow up like him.
Have you seen many weapon spirits?
A few, I suppose.
It is said that the Mute Lady of Wu Mountain is skilled in crafting.
Have you ever created
a divine artifact that can produce weapon spirits?
Of course.
What kind?
A lot.
Nonsense.
If you were really that capable,
you'd be the God of Craft.
Do you
have anything else to do now?
Why?
Come with me.
What?
You haven't
eaten anything all day.
Are you hungry?
When did you buy these?
Just now.
The owner of the noodle shop, Mr. Zhao,
said this shop makes very good dim sum,
so I bought some for you
to try.
Is it good?
Yuanzhong,
don't worry.
Mr. Xu from Qiju Pavilion
wants to hire me
as a craftsman there.
With my skills,
I'll be able to pay back the money soon.
And Xiu
will grow up quickly.
Do you really want Xiu to grow up?
Of course.
Don't you?
Yuanzhong,
after all the weapon spirits
are unsealed,
what do you plan to do?
If you haven't thought about it,
I've already come up with something for you.
What do you have in mind?
These are some excerpts from travel notes
I transcribed from memory.
Look.
"I was to the east of Tanlu Pavilion,
gazing at Chizhou,
delighted by the sight.
Crossing the Imperial River,
treading the Wan Stream,
traversing remote lands,
and drinking a lot of sweet spring water,
I reached the summit of the high mountain
and the source of the river.
Only then did I rest."
What does this describe?
This is about a poet
who accidentally discovered the magnificent scenery of Chizhou.
He crossed the Xiao River,
climbed to the summit of Western Mountain,
beheld the breathtaking landscape,
experienced the charm of nature,
and suddenly felt his heart open
and his spirit become one with the world.
What about this one?
This is about a local custom.
They have a tradition of drinking on ice beds.
People feast joyfully,
offering rare delicacies
and countless fine wines,
drinking heartily on ice beds,
and singing loudly while admiring the snow.
"Idly sitting among the pines,
watching the snow collected from the pine branches melt in the pot."
Exactly.
This is a celestial phenomenon
recorded in A Trip to Yongguan.
It tells
of a strange sight
in the sky there—
on a long night,
a five-colored light appeared,
shaped like a dragon or snake, illuminating the land,
and it didn't disappear until half a month later.
The sky there is colorful.
A colorful sky?
Yes.
There are countless
famous scenic spots and beautiful landscapes
in this world.
Each place has its own scenery and customs.
Yuanzhong,
after Xiu grows up
and Ling Yao's seal is lifted,
you should travel around
and explore the world.
You can see how flowers bloom,
how the rain falls,
see the ice beds of the far north,
and the underground fire in the southern border.
Just go wherever you want
and live wherever you like.
How does that sound?
If I go traveling,
what about you?
Of course I'll go with you.
If Zi Fei and the others are willing,
they can come along too.
Yuanzhong,
this world is vast,
far beyond the grudges between the Youhu Clan
and the War Demons.
Go and see it for yourself
and live some lighthearted days.
You can see how flowers bloom,
how the rain falls,
see the ice beds of the far north,
and the underground fire in the southern border.
Just go wherever you want
and live wherever you like.
Yuanzhong,
this world is vast,
far beyond the grudges between the Youhu Clan
and the War Demons.
Go and see it for yourself
and live some lighthearted days.
How could this happen?
Deity Taihe's body
may not last much longer.
Once his divine body collapses
and he has no other body to attach to,
I'm afraid
he'll soon vanish from this world.
What rotten luck.
We took on such a wretched task.
Stop complaining.
The construction in the city can't be completed.
If we don't get them to do it, who will?
Are you going to do it, or should I?
Look at them.
They're all beggars and vagrants.
They're so hungry that they're almost fainting.
How could they have the strength to work?
We just need to gather enough people
and hand over the required headcount.
How many more do we need?
One.
Well, here's one right here.
Stop.
Where's your pass?
You brat, playing dumb with me, huh?
Waiter!
Coming!
Come.
What should we do now?
What should we do this time?
Once we enter the city, we'll be doing hard labor.
Bro,
do you want to come up with a plan
to leave here with us?
Yes, bro.
Once we enter the city, there will be nothing good waiting for us.
Exactly.
Let's hit the road.
Let's go.
They ran away!
Stop!
Keep an eye on them!
Get up! I said get up!
Get up!
[City Lord's Mansion]
Young Mistress Dai.
You're here.
How are you feeling? Are you better now?
Much better.
The medicine from Dr. Zhang
is really effective.
Then I must thank him properly.
Young Mistress.
The medicine is ready.
I still have things to do in the kitchen,
so please feed him the medicine for me.
-Okay.
-No need.
Well... thank you.
Have one of these.
No need.
Have one. The medicine is very bitter.
You've never tried it.
How do you know it's bitter?
I...
I just know.
It's too sweet.
Is it really that sweet?
Eating sweet things like this every day,
be careful your teeth might fall out when you get old.
My teeth are fine.
They won't fall out when I'm old.
Really?
I've been old before, remember?
Always seeing you like this,
I really have forgotten.
What does it feel like
to age?
Actually, it's not that bad.
It's just that...
my energy was waning day by day;
I couldn't run or jump high,
and walking became slower and slower.
At first, it was hard to accept,
but gradually, I got used to it.
Sometimes, I wonder,
if in this world,
there were no Youhu Clan,
no immortal sects,
no cultivators,
and no gods,
perhaps we humans
would more easily
accept aging.
Perhaps.
Comparisons breed discontent.
All the suffering in this world
comes from discontent.
Even someone like my father
can't see through the cycle of life and death.
How much longer will it take for your father to exit seclusion?
It should be some time.
Don't worry.
Shen Ying and your subordinates
are still investigating Wushuang Society.
I've already
informed my brother about this.
Yandu will never allow anyone
to secretly communicate with the War Demons.
We will definitely
investigate this thoroughly
and give you an explanation.
Thank you.
There's no need to thank me.
The War Demons are also our enemies.
Whoever came up with this plan
of inciting stronger enemies to eliminate weaker ones
is truly shortsighted.
Inciting stronger enemies to eliminate weaker ones?
You're really direct, aren't you?
What do I have to hide from you?
Although we humans have always been oppressed
by the Youhu Clan,
if the War Demons rise,
they'll be after our lives.
The weak always get beaten.
What's the use of complaining?
It's better to work hard to develop ourselves,
and sooner or later, there will be a day
when we can have an equal conversation.
Let's not talk about this anymore.
Is this for me?
I was afraid you might get bored.
What are these?
How is it going?
Shh, they're talking.
This is a puzzle.
When you're tired from reading,
you can work on these.
It's very simple.
Are you sure this is simple?
I used to do puzzles all the time when I was a kid.
I can teach you.
It's here.
I was about to find it.
♫Listening♫
♫Toona leaves knock fireflies into a vase♫
♫Ripples faintly spreading♫
This is your puzzle.
♫In the pavilion in the clouds♫
♫Warm wine brews to the sound of the zither♫
You've done it before,
so it's easier for you to do it again.
♫The fragrance lingers like brush strokes, sketching out your form♫
This is a new one I had someone buy.
My old puzzles from when I was a kid
♫Tonight♫
are many years old,
♫In a light intoxication, I feel the longing in the crystalline snow♫
and they're long gone.
♫I cannot bear to think of you♫
♫I only wish♫
♫That the years would remain ever sunny♫
You can't find it again?
♫So that, within the drifting light, I could share the breeze with you♫
It's here.
I can find it.
♫The wind blows♫
♫It stirs the scenery♫
♫It awakens our heart♫
♫It makes me certain that you are my destiny♫
♫The closer we get♫
♫The more it feels like a dream♫
♫And the more I look intoxicated♫
♫I cannot fully express my yearning for you♫
♫The wind blows♫
♫It blows away the shadows of the clouds♫
♫It makes the moon seem even brighter♫
♫It makes me wake up from a dream♫
♫The wind blows♫
♫It reddens my eyes♫
♫It warms the promise we made♫
♫In the wind, we gently♫
♫Drift into a better place♫
♫The wind blows♫
♫It stirs the scenery♫
Not bad.
♫It awakens our heart♫
I'll take that as a compliment.
♫It makes me certain that you are my destiny♫
I am complimenting you.
♫The closer we get♫
♫The more it feels like a dream♫
Hurry up and try again.
♫And the more I look intoxicated♫
♫I cannot fully express my yearning for you♫
Here.
♫The wind blows♫
♫It blows away the shadows of the clouds♫
♫It makes the moon seem even brighter♫
♫It makes me wake up from a dream♫
♫The wind blows♫
♫It reddens my eyes♫
♫It warms the promise we made♫
♫In the wind, we gently♫
♫Drift into a better place♫
Young City Lord.
They caused such a big mess?
The scouts from Orange Lake reported that
the High Priest of the Youhu Clan and his group
have headed toward Su River.
Our people have already been following them.
Just follow them from a distance.
They are not ordinary people.
Don't draw their attention.
Rest assured, Young City Lord.
What is this High Priest
really thinking?
Since he has already broken the seal,
why doesn't he
take action against the Council of Elders?
He once held a high position,
with the strength of a demigod.
After being imprisoned
and enduring much torture,
he has finally escaped.
Yet, he's not seeking revenge on them.
Could it be
that he has really transcended human emotions,
no longer harboring any feelings
of love, hate, or resentment?
Or perhaps...
he doesn't hold a grudge against his own people
and only wishes to deal with the War Demons?
If that's the case, it could be troublesome.
What about Shen Ying?
Is he still with the Youhu people
recently?
Yes.
They've been very close lately
and are investigating Wushuang Society.
Some clues are already very close.
Our people are working to intervene.
How is Mr. Tanghua's injury?
It's getting better.
What about him and Zhi Dai?
I've had people keep an eye on them.
The two of them
are getting along very well.
Getting along very well?
Miss Ji.
You overpaid me, Mr. Xu.
My things
aren't worth so much silver.
And I still owe you money.
I didn't overpay you.
This is all you deserve.
Well then, thank you very much.
Is this a new treasure you got?
I've never seen it before.
You really have a great eye.
This item is extraordinary.
Watch closely, Miss.
Its magic
is yet to come.
It's truly exquisite.
It doesn't seem like magic.
It's just ordinary clay,
fired
and coated with a layer of gold powder.
There's nothing particularly special about it.
This is the work of the great painter,
Mr. Qi.
Mr. Qi?
Well,
was the statue of the Goddess in the main hall of the dance house
also painted by him?
I really don't know.
Take care, Miss Ji.
Please come again another day.
Truly a masterpiece.
How was it made?
Young City Lord, you're here.
You seem so happy.
What treasure did you get this time?
I did indeed get a treasure,
and I was about to present it to you, Young City Lord.
-Thank you, sir.
Take care.
Who gave me this silver?
How much is this?
This...
Xue?
Long time no see.
Tell me, what strange thing
did you do to me while on the boat?
W-what strange thing?
I didn't do anything.
Nonsense.
I asked around after I came back.
You said you were my neighbor,
but why didn't any of the people I know
recognize you?
You must have used some kind of sorcery on me.
Well...
Really?
Really.
I had no other choice at the time.
I had to find him
right away.
Otherwise, we all would have been in trouble.
I know.
After you all left,
everyone said that the High Priest of the Youhu Clan
saved us.
And without you,
I'm afraid I wouldn't have survived.
But no matter if you're my childhood friend or not,
you left without saying a word,
and that really made me angry.
I had to go after him at that time.
Alright.
I'll forgive you then.
Well, you're not my neighbor anymore,
but an immortal's handmaiden
who can use magic.
You're a big shot now.
Do you still want to be my friend?
Of course!
I'm so happy
to meet you again
here in Yandu.
Waiter! Waiter!
Pack some date cakes for me.
I'm taking them with me.
Alright!
Let me tell you,
the date cakes here are delicious.
Take some back
for your High Priest to try.
I'm sure he'll like them.
Really?
Try some.
It tastes so good.
Right?
Make way! Make way!
Hurry up!
Hurry!
Move!
Make way! Make way!
Hurry up!
So you moved out?
After I left the Shen family's tower ship,
I got quite a bit of pay.
When I came back, I rented a big courtyard
and now I live alone.
Let me tell you,
my place is really big.
It's not crowded no matter how many people live here.
I'm thinking of
subletting two rooms
to make some extra money
and also make the place a bit livelier.
Make way! Make way!
Hurry up!
Hurry up, all of you!
Move!
Hurry up! Move it!
What do they do?
They're all laborers for the workshop.
Many of them are vagrants who were caught here.
Why is he here?
Do you know anyone among them?
You just said that
as long as there's enough money,
they can be ransomed?
Come with me.
Brat,
were you the one who snitched earlier?
Playing mute, huh?
-Teach him a lesson!
-Yes!
You try snitching again
and see what happens!
Stop.
They're all here.
Pick whoever you want.
I want him.